schoolmint.net 2017-02-20

# SchoolMint is Committed to the Highest Privacy Standards

## Our Pledge to Student Privacy

SchoolMint is committed to maintaining student privacy and safeguarding students’ personal information. To demonstrate this commitment, we are proud to be a signatory to the [Student Privacy Pledge](https://studentprivacypledge.org/privacy-pledge/) as a K–12 service provider who has committed to “carry out responsible stewardship and appropriate use of student personal information.”

[Read more](https://studentprivacypledge.org/privacy-pledge/) or [download a PDF](https://studentprivacypledge.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Student-Privacy-Pledge.pdf) of the Student Privacy Pledge.

## SchoolMint’s Commitment to You

SchoolMint, Inc. (the “Company,” “we,” “us,” “our”), knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. By visiting the Company’s website at www.schoolmint.com or any of Company’s other websites, applications, domain names or other linked pages, (collectively the “Website”), or using any of our services, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy. By using the Website, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States.

You post any Content (as that term is defined in the Company’s Terms of Service located at https://www.schoolmint.com/tos.html) on the Website at your own risk. Although we may allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your pages, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you may choose to share your information. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that Content you post on the Website will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Website. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of Content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored your Content.

Any improper collection or misuse of Content or other information accessible on the Website is a violation of the Company’s Terms of Service and should be reported to info@schoolmint.com.

## What does this privacy policy cover?

This Privacy Policy explains how Company collects and uses information from its users who access the Website and use our services, including Company’s treatment of personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”). Also, this Privacy Policy covers Company’s treatment of any Personal Information that Company’s business partners share with Company, or that you provide to the Company through a third party website using a Company application. This policy does not apply to websites or practices of companies that Company does not own or control, or to individuals that Company does not employ or manage.

## How is children’s personal information treated?

If you are a minor (under the age of 18), you may only use this service and disclose Personal Information with your parent or guardian’s express consent. Company collects limited Personal Information from students (“Children’s Personal Information”), but only where that student’s school, district, and/or teacher has contracted with Company to collect Children’s Personal Information from students for the use and benefit of the learning environment. Company requires schools, districts, and/or teachers to obtain parental consent from students’ parents before collecting any such Children’s Personal Information. If you are a student, please do not send any Children’s Personal Information about yourself to us, other than what we request from you when you sign up for the Services. In the event that we learn that we have collected Children’s Personal Information from a student without parental consent being obtained by his or her school, district, and/or teacher, or if we learn a student has provided us Children’s Personal Information beyond what we request when he or she signs up for the Services, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a student may have provided us Children’s Personal Information beyond what is requested when signing up for the Services, or that a student’s school, district, or teacher has not obtained parental consent, please contact us at info@schoolmint.com.

Hereinafter, references to “Personal Information” shall apply to personal information of individual Website users who are not student registrants. References to “Children’s Personal Information” shall only apply to personal information of student users of the Website. General references to “information” shall apply to all users.

## What information does SchoolMint display or collect?

When you use the Website, you may set up your personal profile, send messages, perform searches and queries, and transmit information through various channels, depending on the category of user (“User Category”) you are, and as permitted by the functionality of the Website. The information we gather from users enables us to personalize and improve our services, and, in some cases, to allow our users to set up a user account and profile through the Website. In most cases, we retain such information so that, for instance, you can return to view prior messages you have sent. When you update information, we usually keep a backup copy of the prior version for a reasonable period of time to enable reversion to the prior version of that information. In addition to the foregoing, we collect the following types of information from our users.

## Information You Provide to Us

We receive and store any information you knowingly enter on the Website, whether via computer, mobile phone, other wireless device, or that you provide to us in any other way. This information may include Personal Information such as your name, email address, photograph, and your school affiliation, Children’s Personal Information (which shall be limited to your name and the contact information necessary to receive notifications via the Website from your teacher, school, and/or district (“Notifications”)), and any other information necessary for us to provide our services. You may choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of our features. The Personal Information you provide is used for such purposes as responding to your requests for certain information, products and services, customizing the content you see, and communicating with you about specials and new features. You may modify or remove your Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information identified below at any time by logging into your account and accessing features to edit your classes and/or account information.

## Information Collected Automatically

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with the Website or our services. Company automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, Company cookie information, and the page you requested. We also record the details of your activity on the Website. This information is not Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information.

Generally, our service automatically collects usage information, such as the numbers and frequency of visitors to our site and its components, similar to TV ratings that indicate how many people watched a particular show. Company only uses this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, and not in a manner that would identify you personally. This type of aggregate data enables us to figure out how often users use parts of the Website or services so that we can make the Website appealing to as many users as possible, and improve those services. As part of this use of information, we m  
ay provide aggregate information to our partners about how our users, collectively, use our site. We share this type of statistical data so that our partners also understand how often people use our partners’ services and the Website to help provide you with an optimal online experience.

## Email and Text Message Communications

If you provide us your email address or phone number, we may send you email or text message communications. By maintaining a Company account and/or failing to opt out of the receipt of information hereunder, you acknowledge that you may receive e-mail or text messages on your phone or mobile communications device, and that the receipt of such messages may cause you to incur usage charges or other fees or costs in accordance with your wireless or data service plan. Any and all such charges, fees, or costs are your sole responsibility. You should consult with your wireless carrier to determine what rates, charges, fees, or costs may apply. We may receive a confirmation when you open an email from Company if your computer supports this type of program. Company uses this confirmation to help us make e mails more interesting and helpful.

## What about cookies?

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our site are visited and by how many people. Company cookies do not collect Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information, and we do not combine the general information collected through cookies with other Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information to tell us who you are or what your screen name or email address is.

Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. We strongly recommend that you leave the cookies activated, however, because you will not be able to log in or use many of the Website’s most attractive features without cookies enabled.

## Will SchoolMint share any of the personal information it receives?

Personal Information and Children’s Personal Information about our users is an integral part of our business. We neither rent nor sell your Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information to anyone. However, we share your Personal Information and Children’s Personal Information in personally identifiable form as described below. Again, please note that references to “Personal Information” only apply to personal information of individuals who are not students.

Affiliated Businesses We Do Not Control: In certain situations, businesses or third party websites we’re affiliated with may sell items or provide services to you through the Website (either alone or jointly with us). We may, for example, sell products or provide services jointly with affiliated businesses, or work with third party websites to enhance your online experience. These transactions or services may or may not be commercial in nature; if you are a student, we will not share your Children’s Personal Information in connection with any commercial third party transaction or service. You can recognize when an affiliated business is associated with such a transaction or service, and we will share your Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information with that affiliated business only to the extent that it is related to such transaction or service. Such services may include the ability for you to automatically transmit information you input on the Website to your profile or account on a third party website, or to automatically transmit information you input on a third party website to your Website profile. We have no control over the policies and practices of third party websites as to privacy or anything else, so if you choose to allow the automatic transmissions discussed above, please review all third party websites’ policies before disclosing any Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information or other content on the Website or on any third party website.

Agents: We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you. Examples include sending email, analyzing data, and providing user services. Unless we tell you differently, Company’s agents do not have any right to use Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. You hereby consent to our sharing of Personal Information and Children’s Personal Information for the above purposes.

Communication About the Website or in Response to User Requests: As part of the Website and our services, you may receive from Company (depending on your User Category) email or other types of communication relating to your use of the Website or your user profile. You acknowledge and agree that by posting information on the Website or otherwise using the Website, Company and its agents may send you email, contact you or engage in other communication that they determine in their sole discretion relate to your profile or use of the Website. If you disclose your email address to Company, depending on your User Category, we may use it to send updates, a newsletter or other news regarding the Website or Company services, or to simply send Notifications.

Business Transfers: In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that are transferred. Moreover, if Company, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Company goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquiror of Company may continue to use your Personal Information and Children’s Personal Information as set forth in this policy.

Protection of Company and Others: We may release Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Terms of Service and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Company, our employees, our users, or others. This includes, without limitation, exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection.

With Your Consent: Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be given the option to prevent the sharing of this information.

## Is the information about me secure?

Your Company account Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You may help protect against unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

Company endeavors to protect user information to ensure that user account information is kept private, however, Company cannot guarantee the security of user account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time. For additional information about the security measures Company uses in connection with the Website, please contact us at info@schoolmint.com.

The Website contains links to other sites. Company is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When linking to another site a user should read the privacy policy stated on that site. This Privacy Policy only governs information collected on the Website.

## What information can I access?

Company allows you to access the following information about you for the purpose of viewing, and in certain situations, updating that information. This list may change as the Website changes. You may currently access the following information, if your User Category allows you to input any of the following:

information in your user account, user contacts, user preferences, and content in your account.

## What other choices do I have?

As stated previously, you can always opt not to disclose information, even though it may be needed to take advantage of certain Company features. You are able to add or update certain information on pages, such as those listed in the “What Information Can I Access” section above. When you update information, however, we often maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. Certain types of communication you send to other users cannot be removed, such as messages.

You may request deletion of your Company account by emailing info@schoolmint.com. Please note that some information may remain in our records after deletion of your account. Further, information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent that it was copied or stored by other users. We may use any aggregated data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information after you delete your information, but not in a manner that would identify you personally.

If you do not wish to receive email or other communications or notifications from us, please email us at info@schoolmint.com. Please note that if you do not want to receive legal notices from us, such as this Privacy Policy, those legal notices will still govern your use of the Website, and you are responsible for reviewing such legal notices for changes.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

Company may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time for any reason. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes in the way we use Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information, we will notify you via email or by posting an announcement on the Website. Users are bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when he or she uses the Website after such changes have been first posted.
